Guide to the Alan Sondheim Papers MSS.267
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V. Exhibitions and Events
  - Israel Bond Event - Presentation to Evelyn Sondheim by Judge Max Roseun, Response by Evelyn Sondheim, November 22, 1981 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_279)
  - Sections 1-8 of First Film Series - Supporting Materials for Guggenheim Application, 1981-1982; Duration: Approx. 50 min (Box 1, U-matic 267_568)
    The tape's label says, "Alan Sondheim, sections 1-8 of first film series, 1981-1982, from 16mm optical sound black and white. This series consists of 40+ segments, made at the rate of one reel per week, edited in-camera. They deal with ideology, politicization, the position of the subject, and are made to be shown together."
  - Film Screenings at Art Metropole (Toronto, Canada) - Ephemera, 1981-1983 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Millennium Film Workshop Inc. Personal Cinema Program Calendars, 1983-1993 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Newport Harbor Art Museum Events Calendar, July-August 1983 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - AIR Program (ZBS Studios), 1984 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Cinematheque San Francisco Calendar, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Nexus Contemporary Art Center - Event Posters, 1984-1985 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Nexus Contemporary Art Center - Event Posters, 1984-1987 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Nexus Contemporary Art Center - Event Ephemera, 1984-1987 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Nexus Contemporary Art Gallery - Atlanta Biennale Press Coverage, 1984-1987 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - American Indian Pow-Wow - Grand Prairie, Texas, September 7, 1986 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_135)
  - Halwalls - Event Notes, Ephemera, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Film Forum Calendar, Los Angeles, CA, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "Louise Shaw Makes a Case for Nexus," Open City, June 1987 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - "Immure" Exhibition at the Atlanta Stockade - Photographs, 1987 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Nexus Contemporary Art Center - Atlanta Biennale Press Coverage, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Tre Roberts Exhibition, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits, Screenings, and Events by Various Artists - Posters, 1987-2010 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Exit Art International Forum of Super 8, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Western New York Filmmakers Forum - Screening Flyers, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - "The Figure When It's Speaking" Catalog Essay - World Gallery, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Tyler Stallings Exhibition Slides, 1989-1995 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Film Screenings at Image Film/Video, Atlanta, GA - Ephemera, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - "Photophobia" Video Exhibition, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - "The Red Year" Exhibit, Western Carolina University, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Nexus Exhibition, Includes Opening - Atlanta, January 11, 1991 (Box 14, Hi8 267_382)
  - Selections: Exhibition Consideration Tape: Desperate Thought Rises to the Surface, 1991; Duration: 1 hour 50 min, From Hi8 PCM Stereo (Box 8, Vhs 267_741)
  - Virtual Arm Project - Stelarc, 1992-1993 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Aplets No Mister by Frederic Gafner, December, 1993; Duration: 26 min (Box 7, Vhs 267_660, Box 9, Vhs 267_685)
  - Nexus, September 11, 1993 (Box 16, Hi8 267_404)
  - Exhibition Master: Rainbow @21, Millenium 1994 (Box 8, Vhs 267_739)
  - One0One by Frederic Gafner, September, 1994 (Box 6, U-matic 267_632, Box 7, U-matic 267_649, Box 9, Vhs 267_690, Box 10, Vhs 267_777)
  - Nihon Coin Over by Frederic Gafner, 1994-1995; Duration: 25 min (Box 8, Vhs 267_705, Box 9, Vhs 267_693)
  - On the Vivid by Foofwa D'Imobilité, 1996; Duration: 29 min (Box 9, Vhs 267_700)
  - Stelarc Photographs and Interview, 1996-2001 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_180)
  - Maximax (Work in Progress) by/with Foofwa d'Imobilité, 1997; Duration: 6 min (Box 9, Vhs 267_701)
  - Carte Blanche by Foofwa d'Imobilité, Loup Geneve, 1998 (Box 8, Vhs 267_707)
  - Improvisation at Hot House P.S. 122 - Alan Sondheim and Foofwa D'imobilite, December 6, 1998 (Box 10, Vhs 267_748)
  - Performance in Paris by Foofwa d'Imobilité, February, 1999 (Box 9, Vhs 267_673)
  - Performance in Hellerau by Foofwa d'Imobilité, June 5, 1999 (Box 9, Vhs 267_684, Box 68, Folder 20)
    Includes event flyer in Box 68.
  - Terpsicorp and Marlabor by Foofwa d'Imobilité, September, 1999; Duration: 32 min; color (Box 8, Vhs 267_726, 267_715, Box 9, Vhs 267_676, 267_689, Box 10, Vhs 267_743)
    267_676 is labeled as the "original three performances." 267_689 is labeled as "quickcam shots." 267_743 is labeled as "rough cuts."
  - Catalog Essays and Exhibit Ephemera, 1999-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_171)
  - Dance Performances and Choreographed Videos, 2000-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_174)
  - Event, Exhibition, and Performance Photos, 2000-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_178)
  - Anya Olenbacher Dance with Rehearsal, 2003 (Box 14, Minidv 267_379)
  - One0One by Frederic Gafner - Edit, 2003 (Box 7, Vhs 267_664)
  - Dance Photographs, 2003-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_175)
  - Nom d'artiste: Foofwa d'Imobilite, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - "not-doing" Exhibit at the Paul Mesaros Gallery - Photos, 2004 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_167)
  - "Open Studio" Event Photos, 2005 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_168)
  - Foofwa d'Imobilite - Bio and Performance Ephemera, 2005-2006 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - "Descendance" Dance Series - Artwork, 2006 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_163)
  - "em/bedded" Exhibit at Track 16 Gallery, 2006 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_164)
  - "Flute" Performance - Photos and Audio Recordings, 2006 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_166)
  - Foofwa d'Imobilite - Dance Photos, 2006 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - "Terpsicorp" Dance Series - Artwork, 2006 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_169)
  - 123 Club Performances - Audio and Video Recordings, 2007-2008 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_170)
  - SecondLife Events - Screenshots and Videos, 2007-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_179)
  - "Evam" Dance by Foofwa d'Imobilite and Azure Carter, 2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_165)
  - Dance New Amsterdam - Class and Performance, 2010 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_173)
  - "Air" Exhibit Photgraphs (Montreal and Toronto), Undated (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - "Catch Up" Video Installation Version, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_312)
    The cassette's label notes that the video installation was at Serpentine Galleries in London.
  - "Damaged Life: A Night of Apologies" Poster, Undated (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Dance, Undated (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_509)
  - Dance 1 and 2 - Heidi Trudinger, Undated (Box 3, U-matic 267_592)
    Other labels on the tape say "Heidi: source for knees piece" and "Heidi Hi8 Dub."
  - Dawana Reading, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_319)
  - "The Death of Sean Smith" Exhibit, Texas, Undated (Box 73, Folder 14, 15)
  - "Flesh" Exhibition - University Gallery, North Carolina, Undated (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Franklin Furnace Events Calendar, Undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Frederic Gafner - Unlabeled Dances, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_683, Box 8, Vhs 267_723, Box 68, Folder 19)
  - Geneva Dance Run - Foofwa d'Imobilité, Undated (Box 14, Minidv 267_378)
  - The Ideal Forms: 5 Nude Solo Dances, Undated (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_533)
  - [Illegible] Ex Habitable with Ellis, Roosevelt Island, Etc., Undated (Box 23, 16mm film reels 267_095)
  - "It Doesn't Sound Like Me" Video Installation Version, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_312)
  - "Kit I," Meta Ltd., Undated (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - "Projects in Nature: Eleven Environmental Works," Merriewold West, Far Hills, NJ, Undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Stewart Hannon - Political Tactics and Defense Strategy, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_282)
  - Susan Grant Interview, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_311)
  - Thornton, Greet, Imobilité, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_680)
    titles are illegible
  - "Time Stall," Meta Ltd., Undated (Box 73, Folder 18)
- Series VI. Academic Career
  Series VI. Academic Career includes lecture notes, instructional materials, syllabi, and audiovisual recordings related to classes taught by Sondheim. It also includes documentation of his engagement with academic conferences and symposiums. Sondheim taught New Media at Florida International University from 2001-2002 and Filmmaking at Brown University from 2006-2007. He frequently gives lectures on multimedia art and cyberspace theory, and has appeared at the Cybermind96 Conference, CyPosium, and South by Southwest. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Toronto / UCLA, August, 1966; cuid30319 (Box 24, 8mm film reel 267_142)
  - Course Syllabi, 1968-2000 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Intellectual Interview Determining the Statement and Consistency of Jesis Christ - 3 Interviews, RISD, March, 1971 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_302)
  - Halifax NSCAD, 1972 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_273)
  - "Quinn on Quine" Faculty Systems Group, November 20, 1972 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_267, Box 12, Audiocassette 267_256, 267_262)
  - Alan Sondheim at USCD, May 23, 1974 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_210, Box 14, Audiocassette 267_364)
  - Curricula Vitae, 1974-1990 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Instructional Materials, 1975-2000 (Box 70, Folder 7, 8)
  - Art and Ideology Conference - Preliminary Notes, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - "Critique on the Authentic" read at the Ottawa Art and Ideology Conference, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Pre Convention I and II, August 6, 1981 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_194)
  - Black Mountain College Course Listing Brochure, 1989 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - "Images: Between Art and Life" Lecture Series Poster, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Course Syllabi, 1994-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_189)
  - Instructional Materials, 1994-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_190)
  - Resumes, CVs, and Bios, 1994-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_194)
  - "Mechanical Planet: Genealogies of Virtual Culture" Online Workshop, 1995 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_182)
  - Academic Correspondence, 1995-2007 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_184)
  - Research Proposals and Grant Related Documents, 1995-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_193)
  - Cybermind Conference, 1996 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_172)
  - Cybermind Conference Poster, 1996 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Lectures - Photographs and Notes, 1996-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_191)
  - Conferences and Symposiums - Notes and Documents, 1997-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_187)
  - Webbed Poets Workshop, Albany, 2000 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_195)
  - Conferences and Symposiums - Photographs, 2000-2006 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_188)
  - E-Poetry Photographs, 2001 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_176)
  - "Work on Code" White Paper, 2002-2008 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_183)
  - West Virginia University - Events and Projects, 2004-2009 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_196)
  - Codework Resource Kit, 2005 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_185)
  - E-Poetry Symposium II, 2006 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_177)
  - Brown University MCM 170 Class, c. 2007 (Box 79, 16mm film reels 267_040)
  - Brown University Intro Film, c. 2007 (Box 79, 16mm film reels 267_041)
  - Electronic Media and Film NYSCA Grant Application, 2007 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - "AG Asia Pacific Bounce" Event at West Virginia University, 2008 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_181)
  - Codework Workshop - Schedule of Events, 2008 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_186)
  - Interrupt Conference Poster, 2008 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Interrupt: Language-Driven Digital Art Festival, 2008 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Conference - Notes and Audio Recordings, 2008 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_192)
  - Cal Arts, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_271, 267_298)
  - Class on Music at Newcastle, Conducted with Stuart Marshall, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_362, Audiocassette 267_265)
  - Halifax Convention, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_318)
  - Humanities, Arts, Science, and Technology Advanced Collaboratory Conference (HASTAC) - Schedule and Conference Information, Undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Institute for the Future Notes, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_306)
  - Lecture on Photography - Newcastle, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_323)
  - Notes - Full Explanation?, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_213)
  - RISD English Class, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_242)
  - Speech Tape, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_286)
- Computer Program Backups, 1988-2007 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_197)